52. Northern Lights The beautiful northern lights sweep across
the northern skies. Sometimes they look like blue or green smoke. Sometimes they look like
a vast white scarf shaken out between the stars. They appear mysteriously, as if from
another world, and they have been inspiring mankind for centuries. The Cree people called
them the Dance of the Spirits. Some ancient Norse thought the lights were reflections
off the shields of fallen ancient soldiers going to their paradise. Others thought they
were oceans surrounded by fire. The red lights can also look like a breath of fire from a
dragon. In fact, they may be a source of dragon myths. Red lights were often thought to predict
wars. Some cultures hide when the northern lights are in the sky. Others watch them with
respect. Many Asian cultures believe children born under northern lights will be lucky,
but some European cultures believe the opposite. These mysterious lights that inspire our imaginations
really do come from another world. They come from the sun. The northern lights, or aurora
borealis, their scientific name, result from solar wind connecting with particles high
in Earth's atmosphere. This connection causes the particles to give off different substances. When
there are storms on the sun, we see more auroras because there's more solar wind. The different
colors of the auroras are a result of different particles release different substances. All this
activity can cause problems for radios and other electronic tools, though it creates unbelievable
art in the sky. The northern lights are still a source of inspiration for human beings.
Photographers, painters, writers, they all try to capture the awe that these lights create. However,
these lights are difficult to pin down on paper. You may just have to see them for yourself.